Mukhtar Raji

eaverine1@gmail.com (+234) 09080711942 / 08026102247 https://www.linkedin.com/in/mukhtar-o-raji https://github.com/eaverine, https://medium.com/@eaverine1

Summary

An experienced Software Developer with a high demonstration of problem-solving skills which is frequently exhibited when he is busy mixing Python with data.

With an intermediate experience level in Business Marketing and Customer Service, He also appreciates talent, hard work and customer satisfaction.

Professional Soft Skills

- · Problem Solving
- · Leadership and Communication
- Teaching/Mentoring

- Financial Management
- · Marketing, sales and customer service

Technical Skills

Tools & Technologies he is acquainted with:-

- -- Data Science & Machine Learning :: Python, Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn.
- -- Data Analysis :: Excel, Tableau, Python.
- -- Desktop App Development :: Python, Tkinter.
- -- Desktop Digital Automation :: Python, Selenium, BeautifulSoup, openpyxl, ezsheets, ezgmail, smtplib, imapclient, pyautogui.

Accomplishments

As a Python developer with a high level of experience in building desktop apps, automating digital tasks and implementing Artificial Intelligence solutions, He has built amazing products.

Some apps worthy of mention are:

- 'Easy Peasy Campaigns' which automates ads report download using Amazon
 Advertising api for developers. The app also showcases a visualizer which plots graphs
 and produces other visual cues in order to provide detailed insights into the report data.
- 'Emshol Auto-Data-Entry' which automates bus attendance by getting the attendance from WhatsApp and automatically fills the passengers details on Excel.
- 'Maser Reservation App' which records clients details on SQL and based on this data, it uses Artificial Intelligence to predict client's travel behavioural pattern which helps in giving customized deals to clients.

Employment History

Data Scientist

Hamoye (Internship) • Remote 07/2021 - Present

Developed several machine learning algorithms using Python to train models in predicting data.

Furnished my data science skills in Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn and Scikit-Learn.

Desktop App Developer

Emshol (Contract) • Remote 10/2020 - 01/2021

The contract main goal was to build an easy-to-use app which automates the attendance for passengers into an excel sheet.

The app when completed eased the stress of navigating excel, saved time with a proven time reduction from 24 hours to under an hour for several destinations and returned a zero error attendance.

Software Developer

Fiverr (Freelance) • Remote 10/2018 - Present

One of my proudest project on the platform is a data visualization app for product performance. The app also includes an automatic product report downloader which automatically downloads reports from Amazon Advertising API.

Volunteer Experience

Software Programming Instructor

University Of Ilorin, Ilorin. June 2019

He organized and lectured on a short course on Matlab for over 60 students preparing for exams.

Education & Certifications

Data Analysis Virtual Experience

EntryLevel • Remote 08/2021

Participated in an automated virtual program where He learned and implemented the following with several mentors in the Data Analytics field.

- Learned how to determine a business problem
- Learned a number of data cleaning and manipulation methods using Excel/Google Sheets
- Created Pivot Tables to show key insights with a dataset
- · Learned basic functionality of Tableau and created data visualizations
- Earn the Critical Thinker, Independent Learner and Last Minute Hustle badgs.

B.Engr

University of Ilorin • Ilorin, Kwara Graduating

A student of Electrical/Electronics Engineering with a C.G.P.A in the Second Class Upper Division. Currently working on programmes related to skill acquisition and self development.

High School Education

Adroit Private Schools. • Lagos, Lagos Graduated - 10/2015

Being the assistant school prefect, He represented the school in competitions and was actively involved in a lot of extra curricula activities such as the Jet Club for science students and sports activities.

And being the assistant Imam of the school Mosque, He was actively involved in leading congregational prayers, and lecturing.

Languages

- English
- Arabic

- Yoruba
- French